const e="crk",t=200,o=75,a=[{id:148,question:"In his second letter to the Christians in Thessalonians, Paul admonished them to have nothing to do with anyone who refused to obey what he wrote in the letter. What did Paul think would happen to the person?  ",option:{a:"The person would be encouraged  ",b:"The person would be ashamed  ",c:"The person would be disturbed  ",d:"The person would repent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:149,question:"In the Sermon on the Mount, the meek are blessed because  ",option:{a:"They shall see God  ",b:"They shall be exalted  ",c:"They shall inherit the earth  ",d:"They shall be called sons of God "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:150,question:"Which of the following is not a natural miracle:  ",option:{a:"Stilling of the storm  ",b:"Walking on the sea  ",c:"Raising of Lazarus from the dead  ",d:"Feeding the five thousand"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:151,question:"The prophet whose message was primarily on social justice and true religion is  ",option:{a:"Isaiah  ",b:"Agabus  ",c:"Amos  ",d:"Jeremiah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:152,question:"The prophet who prophesied that Paul would be arrested in Jerusalem is  ",option:{a:"Isaiah  ",b:"Agabus  ",c:"Philip  ",d:"Stephen  "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:153,question:"One of the lessons one can derive from the story of Deborah the Prophetess is that  ",option:{a:"Women are not good warriors  ",b:"Women should not be allowed to take leadership roles  ",c:"Women’s rights should be fought for by all ",d:"God can use anyone regardless of their gender and tribes."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:154,question:"One of the following is not among the reasons why Jesus taught in Parables  ",option:{a:"to fulfill the prophecy in Psalm 78:2  ",b:"to create understanding  ",c:"to make people learn the unknown through the known  ",d:"to show the omniscient power of Jesus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:155,question:"The disciple in Damascus who prayed for Saul (Paul) to receive his sight after his conversions was  ",option:{a:"Ananias ",b:"Sapphira  ",c:"Barnabas  ",d:"Thomas "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:156,question:"According to James, one of the causes of wars among Christians is ",option:{a:"their passions  ",b:"their wickedness  ",c:"their faith without work  ",d:"their pride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:157,question:"One of the following was not among the decisions reached at the Council of Jerusalem concerning the Gentiles who became Christians:  ",option:{a:"That Gentiles should obtain from what has been sacrificed to idols  ",b:"The Gentiles should abstain from blood  ",c:"That Gentiles should abstain from what is strangled ",d:"That Gentiles should abstain from love of the world "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:158,question:"“Thy glory, O Israel upon thy high places! How are the mighty fallen! Tell it not in the streets of Ashkelon… How  are the mighty fallen in the midst of the battle!” The above dirge was written by David when  ",option:{a:"He killed Goliath  ",b:"Uriah the Hittite died  ",c:"Saul and Jonathan died  ",d:"Abner was killed by Joab"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:159,question:"Who was one of the Seven Deacons who had four daughters who were prophetesses?  ",option:{a:"Nicolaus  ",b:"Stephen  ",c:"Prochorus  ",d:"Philip "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:160,question:"According to the Letter to the Hebrews, why should Christians lay aside every weight and sin which clings so closely?  ",option:{a:"Sin is contagious  ",b:"Christian can easily be influenced by sinners  ",c:"Christians are surrounded by so great a cloud of witness  ",d:"No sinner will inherit the kingdom of God "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:161,question:"“To obey is better than sacrifice” came from  ",option:{a:"Prophet Daniel  ",b:"Prophet Ezekiel  ",c:"Prophet Elijah  ",d:"Prophet Samuel "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:162,question:"The three sons of Saul who lost their live on Mount Gilboa were  ",option:{a:"Jonathan, Ishbosheth and Abinadab  ",b:"Abinadab, Jonathan and Ishbosheth  ",c:"Jonathan, Abinadab and Malchisua  ",d:"Ishbosheth, Malchishau and Abinadab"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:163,question:"The original name of Shadrach was  ",option:{a:"Daniel  ",b:"Mishael  ",c:"Hananiah  ",d:"Azariah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:164,question:"The person who was invited to nurse Moses was ",option:{a:"Jochebed  ",b:"Puah  ",c:"Shiphrah  ",d:"Miriam "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:165,question:"“… But let judgment run down as waters, and righteousness as a mighty stream… “Fairness, judgment and righteousness were set aside during the time of  ________ for burnt and meat offerings.",option:{a:"Amos  ",b:"Hosea  ",c:"Ezekiel  ",d:"Hezekiah "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:166,question:"Eli’s inability to discipline his sons led to all the following except  ",option:{a:"God’s curse on his family  ",b:"the extension of his life span  ",c:"the cancellation of priesthood from his lineage",d:"the death of his sons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:167,question:"Who was the King of Judah who witnessed the second deportation?  ",option:{a:"Gedaliah  ",b:"Jehoiachin  ",c:"Zedekiah ",d:"Jehoiakim"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:168,question:"Paul, the apostle to the gentile, was a native of  ",option:{a:"Perga in Pamphylis  ",b:"Rome  ",c:"Jerusalem  ",d:"Tarsus "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:169,question:"In the Sermon on the Mount, Jesus taught his disciples that whenever they faced persecution, they should  ",option:{a:"be more serious with their drive for souls ",b:"be rejoiced and be exceedingly glad  ",c:"withdraw and  be less active  ",d:"resist persecution and fight for their rights  "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:170,question:"According to Peter, Judgment of God must first begin in  ",option:{a:"the house of God  ",b:"the public places  ",c:"the midst of criminals ",d:"the government auditoria "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:171,question:"Paul told the believers in Corinth that no one can say Jesus is Lord except by  ",option:{a:"knowledge  ",b:"revelation  ",c:"grace  ",d:"the Holy Spirit "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:172,question:"Render to Caesar the things that they are Caesar’s and to God the things are God’s, the above quotation emphasizes  ",option:{a:"Obedience to divine authority  ",b:"Striking a balance between civil and divine authorities ",c:"Disobedience to civil authority  ",d:"Total rejection of both divine and civil authorities"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:841,question:"Darkness was not created during creation because",option:{a:"the earth was full of water",b:"God’s spirit was over the waters",c:"darkness was already in existence",d:"God wanted to have day and night"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:842,question:"The two creation stories agree that",option:{a:"man and woman were created on the same day",b:" creation was carried out by spoken word",c:"there was existing land mass before creation",d:"creatures created were to be fruitful and multiply"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:843,question:"Joseph was of a good behaviour because he",option:{a:"was loved and pampered by his father",b:"interacted well with his prision inmates",c:"rejected Potiphar’s wife proposal",d:"served diligently in Potiphar’s house"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:844,question:"“Do you mean to kill me as you killed the Egyptian?”This statement made Moses aware of the fact that ",option:{a:"some Israelites did not like him",b:"God was sending him to Midian",c:"Pharaoh was looking for his arrest",d:"His killing of an Egyptian was known"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:845,question:"God made Pharaoh to chase and bring the Israelites back to Egypt so that He would",option:{a:"show that Moses was his true servant",b:"destroy first born males of Egyptians",c:"get glory over Pharaoh and his hosts",d:"reveal his supernatural powers to the world"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:846,question:"The minority report of the twelve spies was presented by",option:{a:"Caleb and Joshua",b:"Palti and Gaddiel",c:"Joshua and Ammiel",d:"Sethur and Gaddiel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:847,question:"Moses asked God for a new leader for Israel so that lsrael might",option:{a:"have a shepherd",b:"conquer the Cannanites",c:"own the Promised land",d:"become a greater nation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:848,question:"Moses before his death served lsrael as",option:{a:"prophet, liberator and king",b:"king, priest and warrior",c:"priest, prophet and deliverer",d:"strategist, seer and prophet"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:849,question:"Beside being a true prophetess, Deborah could also be described as a woman of",option:{a:"love",b:"glory",c:"peace",d:"charity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:850,question:"“Give meat for the priest to roast for he will not accept boiled meat from you, but raw”This request was wrong because in a peace offering",option:{a:"meat with blood was unacceptable ",b:"juicy meat went to the worshippers",c:"the fat were burnt before  any distribution",d:"priests were entitled to the right thigh and breast"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:851,question:"Which of the following people destroyed Shiloh and captured the Ark? The",option:{a:"Ammonites",b:"Amalekites",c:"Palestinians",d:"Philistines"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:852,question:"Samuel said that rebellion was as the sin of divination just as stubbornness was as ",option:{a:"iniquity and adultery",b:" sinful as disobedience",c:"iniquity and murder",d:"sinful as adultery"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:853,question:"“Has the Lord as great delight in burnt offerings and sacrifices as in obeying the voice of Lord? These words were directed to king",option:{a:"Ahab",b:"Saul",c:"Agag",d:"David"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:854,question:"After Saul’s death on Mount Gilboa, the Philistines",option:{a:"burnt his body near the tamarisk tree",b:"sent his head to Dagon their god",c:"made a sport of him at Bethshan",d:"buried his sons in a mass grave"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:855,question:"Although David was regarded as a man after God’s heart, he acted badly before God when he",option:{a:"refused to slay Saul in the wilderness of Kish",b:"remained at home while his troops were on the battlefield",c:"imprisoned Nathan for condemning him",d:"committed sin of adultery and murder"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:856,question:"The Hebrew kingdom broke up beacuse of ",option:{a:"prophet Ahijah’s curse against solomon",b:"Solomon’s marriage to foreign women",c:"Rehoboam’s efforts to rule Shechem",d:"Rehoboam’s refusal to grant the Northerners’ petition"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:857,question:"Ahab revealed his disregard for the law when he",option:{a:"got married to Jezebel",b:"persecuted the prophets of lsrael",c:"appropriated the vineyard of Naboth",d:"refused to listen to Naboth"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:858,question:" Josiah sent the ashes of the burnt vessels of Baal to Bethel in order to",option:{a:"desecrate the golden calf being worshipped",b:"desecrate the place for child sacrifice",c:"despoil the high places of Asherah",d:"consecrate that place for Yahweh worship"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:859,question:"King Nebuchadnezzar mounted his golden image on/at",option:{a:"the plain of Dura",b:"the plain of Jericho",c:"the sea of Arabah",d:"susa of Babylon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:860,question:"Daniel  disobeyed King Darius by",option:{a:" refusing to honour the Persian gods",b:"refusing to be made president of the Satraps",c:"celebrating Jewish festival in a foreign land",d:"praying three times daily for thirty days"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:861,question:"The Judean King who revolted against Babylon after serving her for three years was",option:{a:"Jehoahaz",b:"Jehoiakim",c:"Jehoiachin      ",d:"Zedekiah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:862,question:"Nehemiah showed concern for this nation by",option:{a:"reviving Yahweh worship",b:"rebuilding the temple",c:"reconstructing Jerusalem walls",d:"leading exiles home"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:863,question:"The tribes which lead the Jews in rebuilding the temple were",option:{a:"Judah and Benjamin",b:" Levi and Gad",c:"Ephraim and Manasseh",d:"Reuben and Zebulum"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:864,question:"Amos satirically invited the Jews to come to Bethel and Gilgal in order to",option:{a:"repent",b:"worship",c:"transgress",d:"pacify"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:865,question:" Hosea described the relationship between God and Israel as",option:{a:"a covenant contract",b:"a marriage bond",c:"a marriage reunion",d:"an agreement bond"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:866,question:"Jesus’ baptism was significant because it",option:{a:"initiated him into Judaism",b:"cleansed Him from sin",c:"awakened the messianic spirit in Him",d:"marked the call into the messianic ministry"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:867,question:" “If you are the son of God, throw yourself down from here”This temptation implies that Jesus should",option:{a:"win followers through the use of spectacular miracles",b:"win coverts through the supply of basic needs",c:"allow angels to minister unto Him",d:"use scriptures to overcome the devil"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:868,question:"The two Old Testament books that were used in the temptation stories were",option:{a:"Genesis and Proverbs",b:"Leviticus and Lamentation",c:" Numbers and Ecclesiates",d:"Deuteronomy and Psalms"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:869,question:"“For he was astonished, and all that were with him, at the catch of fish which they had taken”The people being referred to in the text were",option:{a:"Matthew, John and Andrew",b:"Matthias, John and Peter",c:"James, Peter and John",d:"Simon, Andrew and Thomas"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:870,question:"Jesus taught that Christians should forgive their neighbours’ sin",option:{a:"three time only",b:"seventy times seven times",c:"seventy-seven times seven times",d:"as many times as possible"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:871,question:"In the garden of Gethsemane, Jesus",option:{a:"was arrested",b:"was crucified",c:"rebuked Judas Iscariot",d:"prayed for peace"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:872,question:"During Jesus’ trial, some people discovered that Peter was Jesus’ fellower because of his",option:{a:"The preference of Barabbas to Jesus",b:"The question of payment of tribute",c:"Accusation of Jesus as a rioter",d:"The seeking of false witness against Jesus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:873,question:"Which of the following incidents occurred during Jesus’ trial before Caiaphas?",option:{a:"The preference of Barabbas to Jesus",b:" The question of payment of tribute",c:"Accusation of Jesus as a rioter",d:"The seeking of false witness against Jesus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:874,question:"Discipline requires self- denial and complete",option:{a:"tolerance ",b:"forgiveness",c:"commitment",d:"purification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:875,question:"“This is the King of the Jews”This inscription on the cross was meant to show Jesus",option:{a:"charge ",b:"punishment ",c:"victory       ",d:"messiaship"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:876,question:"How many groups of people mocked at Jesus on the cross ",option:{a:"Two",b:"Three",c:" Four",d:" Four "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:877,question:"“Mary Magdalene and the other Mary went to see the sepulchre”. “The other Mary”, according to St. Mark was the mother ",option:{a:"James and Joses",b:"James and John",c:"Smon and Andrew",d:" Thomas and John Mark"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:878,question:"The resurrection stroy encourage Christians to believe that the Lord they adore is",option:{a:"still alive today",b:"a miracle working God",c:"Lord over evils",d:"powerful and Just"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:879,question:"As a result of Peter’s speech on Pentecost day",option:{a:"the dispute over drunkenness was resolved",b:"the prophecies of Joel were vindicated",c:"the religious leaders accepted Jesus’ resurrection",d:"many Jewish souls joined christianity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:880,question:"To which religious party did Gamaliel belong? The",option:{a:"Zealots",b:"Sadducees",c:"Pharisees      ",d:"Herodians"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:881,question:`And we are witnesses to these  things, and so is the Holy Spirit whom God has given to those who obey him”
 “These things” in the disciples’ statement before the
 Sanhedrin refers to
`,option:{a:"the election of Matthias",b:"outpouring of the Holy Spirit",c:"cater for the poor and needy",d:"defend Christianity as a true religious "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:882,question:"The importance of the parable of the unmerciful servant is that Christians should",option:{a:"allow mercy to take precedence over justice",b:"avoid discrimination  against one another",c:"be faithful and not to betray their trust",d:"use wealth diligently and honestly"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:883,question:"The visitors of Peter after his vision at Joppa were ",option:{a:"Jerusalem",b:"Samaria",c:"Caesarea",d:"Antioch"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:884,question:"The visitors of Peter after his vision at Joppa were from ",option:{a:"Jerusalem",b:"Samaria",c:"Caesarea",d:"Antioch"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:885,question:"When Rhoda reported that Peter was at the door, the inmates retorted that",option:{a:"“you are a liar”",b:"“you are mad”",c:"“Peter is dead”",d:"Peter is alive”"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:886,question:"James maintained that the double-minded man would not have his prayers answered because he",option:{a:"is unstable in all his ways",b:"asks for things with selfish motives",c:"prays with unforgiving hearts",d:"intercedes with a sinful heart"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:887,question:`
 Which of the following, accordings to James is an important
 factor for effective prayer?
`,option:{a:"Love",b:"Faith",c:"Hope",d:"Mercy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:888,question:"Partially according to James is manifested in the Church through",option:{a:"discrimination",b:"charity",c:"affection",d:"impartiality"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:889,question:"To be a good citizen, Peter advised believers to honour all men and",option:{a:"live as free men",b:"love the brotherhood",c:"obey their lawful masters",d:"love reading the scriptures"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:890,question:"Peter encourage the church to humble themselves before  God so that He would",option:{a:"exonerate them",b:"not punish them",c:"exalt them",d:"not disown them"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"}],s={subject:e,status:200,total:75,data:a};export{a as data,s as default,t as status,e as subject,o as total};
